Dr.VASHI PAYAL (PT)

Musculoskeletal Science & Sports

+44-7880811164

vashi31payal@gmail.com

https://payalvashi.github.io/

PERSONAL SUMMERY

My professional and academic experience has helped me to develop skills like teamwork, management, communication. Also my passion in musculoskeletal physiotherapy motivates me to enhance my knowledge in the field and stay up-to-date with the new discoveries of advance sports injury prevention as well as rehabilitation. With all my experience, I feel confident of being able to work with any organization successfully.

SKILLS

- Soft tissue manipulation
- Assessment and prevention
- Pilates

- Creative Teaching
- Data management
- Strong verbal communication

EDUCATION

Masters of Physiotherapy – First class with Distinction (7.78 CGPA), **2017**Dr. D.Y.Patil College of Physiotherapy affiliated to D.Y. Patil Vidyapeeth, Pune, Maharashtra

Bachelor of physiotherapy - First class with Distinction (7.55 CGPA), 2014

Ashok & Rita Institute of physiotherapy affiliated to CHARUSAT University, Anand,

Gujarat

WORK HISTORY

Assistant Professor ,From October 2017 to April 2019 Uka Tarsadia, Maliba Bardoli , Surat

- Providing academic knowledge to the students by planning appropriate and engaging lessons for both classroom and clinical posting. Guiding them to identify their interest and strength in literary & theater.
- Monitoring physiotherapy OPDs to maintain quality of patient treatment by interacting with vendors and professional services personnel.

Speaker ,July 2017

AWAKE-awareness programme, Shree M. & N.Virani Science College, Rajkot, Gujarat

• Lecture was delivered on Health of Bone. Advice about importance and source of vitamin D & calcium were given to around 200 women to maintain their nutrition level and avoid osteoporosis. Home based exercise were taught to maintain density of bone.

Sports physiotherapist, 2016

61st National School Games 2015-2016 Taekwondo competition -Pune, Maharashtra

- Educated athletes and trainers regarding diet, injury prevention and therapeutic treatments.
- Monitored and help athletes for quick return to play.
- Planned and administered a first aid and emergency treatments.

Volunteer Physiotherapist, 2015

OXFAM TRAILWALKER, walk for equality-Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Evaluated and treated a wide range of conditions, including acute pain, cramps, Blisters, Sprain, Strain.
- Educated participants and family members regarding maintenance of proper fluid level, injury prevention and therapeutic treatments.

Physiotherapist. Feb 2015 to July 2015

Sparsh Physiotherapy Clinic - Navsari, Gujarat

- Evaluated and treated a wide range of conditions, including chronic and acute pain, disc prolapse, whiplash, dislocations, arthritis, Multiple Sclerosis, Parkinson's, stroke and neuropathies.
- Educated patients and family members regarding diagnosis, injury prevention and therapeutic treatments.
- Monitored and recorded patient progress in response to therapy.

PUBLICATIONS

- Corresponding author Article entitled "Barefooted vs with footwear: functional mobility assessment on community dwelling elders" published in International Journal of Community Medicine and Public Health May 2019 Edition, Volume 6, Issue 5.
- Author-Article entitled "Effect of two Different Movement Patterns of Isotonic Muscle
 Work on Fatigue Index, Power ,Strength and Endurance on Lower Extremity" published
 in International Journal of Scientific and Research Publication May 2017 Edition,
 Volume 7, Issue 5:ICV [2015]:70.03 Impact factor: 3.27, ISSN 22503153.

- **Co-author** -Article entitled "Pelvic Tilt as A Measure of Hamstring Muscle Flexibility in Sit Reach Test" published in **Global Journal for Research Analysis**. May 2017, volume 3, Issue 11:ICV:80.06, Impact factor: 4.547, UGC ISSN 2277 8179.
- Co-author -Article entitled "Reliability of a New Multicomponent Agility Test for Assessing Agility in Basketball Players: The Basketball Multicomponent Agility Test (BMAT)"published in International journal of advance research, ideas and innovations in technology. May 2017, Volume 3, Issue 3:, Impact factor: 4.295, ISSN: 2454-13

	CERTIFICATION	-
 Certified Pilates Instructor 		
	ACHIEVEMENT	

1St Runner up: Poster presentation,

5th National Physiotherapy summit "Phsiofest 2014", held at school of physiotherapy, R.K. University, Rajkot, April 2014.

WORKSHOPS & CONFERENCES

Activity	Title	Organizer	Place	Year
Conference	Multidisciplinary Approach in Shoul- der Joint Dysfunc- tion	Shrimad Rajchandra College of Physiother- apy	Bardoli,Surat	2019
Conference	Multidisciplinary Approach in ACL Re- habilitation	Shrimad Rajchandra College of Physiother- apy	Bardoli,Surat	2018
Workshop	Basics of experi- mental Design	Maliba Pharmacy College	Bardoli,Surat	2018
Conference	2nd Pune Physio Con	Noble Hospital Physiotherapy Department	Pune	2017
Conference	2nd Pune Knee Rehab Course	Tapasvi Charitable trust & Medical Cen- tre	Pune	2017
Workshop	Osteopathy & Modified manipulative therapy Pelvic & Spine	Physio Development Club	Ahmedabad	2017
Workshop	Pilates Instructor Training	Indian Academy Of Fitness Training	Pune	2016
Workshop	Surface and Function Anatomy for Physiotherapist	Life Point Multi-spe- cialty Hospital	Pune	2016

Workshop	Manual therapy (mulligan therapy)	Capri Institute of Manual Therapy	Pune	2015
Conference	8thAnnual Conference of Indian Academy of Cerebral Palsy	Polio Foundation	Ahmedabad	2013
Workshop	Evidence Based Management of Spi- nal Pain	Charotar Institute of Physiotherapy	Ananad	2012

OTHER DETAILS

• D.O.B: 31St August ,1992

• Language Proficiency : English, Hindi, Gujarati

• Marital Status: Married

• Address: 225,The frontage,1 Queen Street,NG1 2BL,United Kingdome